Adim Odumefune

Rochester, NY 14624 odum.abua@gmail.com 585-298-7393

https://iamadim.github.io/adim2page/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-driven professional with 3+ years excelling in a highly collaborative work environment, with demonstrated ability to succeed under tight deadlines. Building products for users, meeting the highest standards for web design, front-end development, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Translating solutions, mockups into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases. I have a strong willingness to learn and master Backend development.

SKILLS

- JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, JSON, Rest, Bootstrap, Ajax, Python
- Databases: MySQL
- Frameworks/Libraries: jQuery, Angular, React, D3, Node JS
- Unit Testing Tool: Jasmine
- Development Methodologies: Agile.
- Software: Dreamweaver, Visual Studio, VSCode, Photoshop, Illustrator
- Version Control: Git

EXPERIENCE

Citibank Buffalo

Web Developer Lead

05/2019-02/2020

Worked directly with Project Managers to design the overall look and feel of websites. A highpressure environment created by timelines, working on multiple projects at the same time, working for demanding clients.

- Hand coded/implemented HTML Emails and innovative landing pages using clean, standards-compliant code in Dreamweaver for email marketing campaigns and newsletters.
- Produced page contents using Bootstrap responsive layout design to fit for different designs and revised code when necessary to ensure campaigns rendered properly across multiple email clients, browsers and mobile devices.
- Converted mockups into HTML, JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery and JSON. Achieved smooth transition from mockup intranet website to a new live website.
- Focused on Cross-browser feature of pages. Implemented tests on Chrome, Firefox, IE with Chrome Developer Tools. Fixed bugs and optimized JavaScript codes.
- Played key role in design and implementation of new projects, new features, components, refactoring, enhancements, updates, fixes, testing and deployment.
- Worked in a collaborative and agile environment.

Environment: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JSON, Photoshop, Illustrator

Front-End Software Engineer

06/2017-11/2018

Worked closely with software development and testing team members onsite at **XEROX** to design and develop robust software solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.

- The front-end use HTML5, CSS3, Angular and Bootstrap to build a single page web app that communicate with C# back-end via REST API.
- Implemented template-driven form validation using Angular 2.
- Enhanced the system to improve user experience and developed functions to acquire data from REST Web Service using Angular 2 and HTTP Observable.
- Worked in a collaborative and agile environment.

Environment: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JSON, Angular, TypeScript, React

PROJECTS: 02/2020-Present

- Currently building a portfolio website using python
- Working on an e-commerce project for a clothing store.

Environment: JavaScript, jQuery, React, Redux, Python, TypeScript, GraphQL

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Computer Science, SUNY College at Brockport, Brockport NY

2017